So, let's get right into it. So, GBPCHF,
I actually ended up taking the same
position two different times. This first
position here, I actually ended up
getting closed out at break even when
price came back. As you guys can see on
this screenshot right here, it's the
first GBPCHF trades where I basically
made $10,000. Yes, $10,000 in profit is
my break even because of the fees that I
have to pay. And then after the trade
came back and took me out of break even,
I then took basically the exact same
trade once again where I did end up
closing this one for the
$415,000 in profit. But I made this
analysis based off of the weekly time
frame because when this market had hit
the bottom of this low, all I simply did
was look left. I'm like, okay, what is
the market doing every single time it
hits this low? Let me see as far back as
I possibly can. And I can see that the
market has never made it this low
before. It has never broken below this
low from September 2022. Every single
time we hit this low, we have a major
reaction to the upside. Every single
time we hit this low, we have a
reaction. Every single time we hit this
low, reaction, low, reaction, and we're
at the low again, what can we
anticipate? A simple reaction. It is
just logic. This is just basic analysis.
Every single time we hit the lowest
point in the market, we're destined to
bounce back. So then here I go down to
the daily time frame and on the daily
time frame I start seeing reversal
patterns. This right here is a beautiful
morning star formation with a bullish
daily pin bar. So I get it. We are
taking a high-risk trade because the
weekly time frame is bearish, the daily
time frame is bearish and then the 4our
time frame is bearish. If all the trends
are indicating to go down, you should
logically look to go down. But if we're
at the lowest point you ever been, you
can't sell to the bottom. You're
basically already at the lowest point.
It's not a logical trade. You expect
from the lowest point for it to have a
bounce. It's almost like if you wanted
to jump into a pool with no water,
you're not going to go anywhere. We're
just going to hit the floor. It doesn't
make sense to jump into the pool. Does
not make sense to sell if we're at the
lowest point. the market is destined to
have a retracement to then maybe break
through back to this area. So after
seeing a beautiful morning star
formation, I then go down to the 4hour
time frame and on the 4 hour I see that
the market has then had a potential
higher low being created. This is
basically the only strong level of
support or resistance that we have on
the lower time frame. So, it's not a
very strong level of support and
resistance because one, it's on the 4
hour and it doesn't really have a lot of
rejections unless I go really, really,
really far back left. And we can tell
that the market has done this in the
past. Whenever we have hit a low, the
market has broken above this area,
retested, and then head to the upside. I
am no rocket scientist. I am no genius.
All I simply did is repeat the exact
same pattern, the exact same line when
we did this back in 2022. All the market
did was break and retest. And here we're
doing the exact same thing. Another
break and retest. It's literally doing
the exact same pattern as it did in
2022. I'm not even applying my strategy
at this point. All I'm doing is just
making the trade make sense. Does it
make more sense to buy or does it make
more sense to sell based off of what the
market is showing? Now that the market
is showing me that it makes more sense
to buy. Now is when I start implementing
my strategy, especially since it's a
counter trend trade, I want to have as
many confluences in my favor as I can.
One of the confluences in my strategy is
this morning star formation right here
as a continuation pattern from where we
are. And if I just look all the way to
the left back when we had created this
same exact pattern right here, I can
tell that the market what it did is it
broke above this area and it created the
exact same morning star formation after
break and retesting this line of
1.07182. So if I just go back to current
price where we are right now, we can see
that we have broken above
1.07182 with the exact same information.
So now I understand that this is
literally creating the exact same
pattern. Then here I go down to the 1
hour time frame. On the 1 hour time
frame I can tell that we are currently
bullish. So part of my strategy is that
I need at least two time frames in sync
in order for us to enter a trade. And
here we happen to have the 1 hour is
bullish. This is the higher low. This is
the higher high. We have a retracement
to this very well respected 1 hour 4hour
area of interest. Very clean level of
support on above. very clean level of
resistance went below and then here we
get a confirmation that we have reacted
from this area. Then I go down to the 30
minute time frame and on the 30-inut
time frame you can tell that we have
created a very strong double bottom. We
have rejected this area of interest
broken above the high and then on these
retracements I entered at the dogee here
anticipating exactly what has happened
which is another morning star formation.
Now what happened with this first
position is that I believed that this
trade well first of all I actually had
my takeprofit be a 1 to2. So my take
profit was around here but then I
believed that this market was going to
continue heading to the upside. We had
broken above this structure point. I
anticipated a retest and then I was
anticipating for this to continue to
this next structure point. So what did I
do? All I did was put my stop loss to
break even and I continued to set and
forget this position. My slogan is set
and forget. Hold the trade until it hits
the highest point or lowest point that
it possibly can because if it broke
through this high, it should retest it
how it did and then it should have a
continuation push to here. So up around
this area, I was probably floating in
profit 380 to
$420,000. And this had a very clean
opportunity to make it up to a 1 to4
risk-to-reward, which would have made me
8 to
$900,000 without me having to add any
extra risk. A lot of traders think that
in order for you to make more money in
the markets, you need to add more trades
and risk more money. That's not entirely
the case. I would have made double the
amount of profit that I was going to
make by simply doing nothing. Just
letting the trade continue moving how
it's supposed to be moving. And I'm all
for that. Making more profits without
adding any more risk. And this gave me
all the indications that I would need in
order for me to let a position run like
this. Obviously came back, took me out
of break even. I did not get mad. I did
not get emotional. It was a decision at
the moment that made sense. I was making
more money without risking more money.
It didn't cost me anything. So I said,
"Let's hold it." Price came back, took
us out of break even. I said, "Okay, you
know what? If I get another morning star
formation exactly how we did before, I'm
simply going to enter the exact same
trade. That's exactly what it did.
Market here gave me another morning star
formation. If anything, confirming that
now we're going to continue heading to
the upside because on the daily time
frame at that moment, we had had a
ginormous bullish candlestick create a
beautiful wick fill. So, I anticipated
the next daily candlestick to be a
retracement for the next the next daily
candlestick to be the continuation. So
on the 4hour time frame, I see the
morning star formation that I
anticipated to the lower time frame for
me to get a beautiful retracement and a
retest of the previous structure point.
So then here is where I can see that
this market was going bearish. Lower
low, lower high, lower low, lower high,
lower low. We shifted bullish, retested
this structure point right here. Very
minor area of interest. And then we have
our EMA along with our tweezer bottoms.
Beautiful entry signal. And then we had
a beautiful 1 to2 risk-to-reward. If you
notice, it is the exact same trade that
I had just taken. But there is one
difference in between this position and
this position and that is that this
position I wanted to continue to hold
but I did not because we were
approaching the weekend. And I tend to
not like to hold trades over the weekend
unless I'm very very very very much in
profit and very far from my entry point.
I saw my entry point here very close.
So, I decided to close this trade at
around
$415,000 in profit, which is where I
could have closed this exact same
position at. And I could have re-entered
it and I would have made a total of
$800,000 by taking the exact same trade
two times. I'm not doing anything
different other than just taking the
exact same trade. And the crazy part of
it is that my original takerit for this
high right here, it actually did get
hit. But if I would have continued to
hold this position throughout the
weekend, the market would have came
back, took me at a break even on the
exact same trade for a second time and
then it would have actually gone
straight to my takerit. So I am very
glad that I stuck to my plan and that I
closed the position on Friday before the
market closed. And then the following
week, I was looking for entries around
this area here. Didn't manage to get the
ones that I exactly wanted. So I did
miss overall the trade that I wanted to
take. But the beauty of it is that I
analyzed the market to perfection. I
anticipated this whole entire weekly
reaction based off of simply just
looking to the left and identifying a
very strong level of support and
resistance. And whenever the market
approaches it, it is very well
respected. Whenever we're above it, we
head up. All we got to do is look for
reasons on why it's going to head up.
So, in this market, not only did I once
get taken out of break even and missed
out on $400,000, but then I again missed
out on an extra $400,000 by not holding
or finding an opportunity to enter even
though I was right about the direction.
Does it suck being right about a trade
and not being able to capitalize off of
that opportunity? Yes. You know what
else sucks is not taking a trade that
follows your trading plan and then you
make a mistake and then you lose money.
I don't mind missing out on a profitable
trade or making money on an opportunity
that did not meet my trading plan. But I
do mind breaking my trading plan and
losing. If I do not break my trading
plan and I lose, I'm okay with that. But
if I break it and I lose, I'm
responsible. And I want to explain to
you why this is a very high risk trade.
So we understand that all of the markets
in order for us to enter it, we have to
identify if it's going up or if the
market is going down. We understand that
in order for the market to go up, we
need a retracement for it to continue to
go up. And we understand for a market to
go down, we need a retracement for it to
continue to go down. So, the way I saw
this market is that we're at a very
strong low, if not one of the lowest
lows we've ever been. As you can tell by
looking to the left, I anticipate that
we should continue to follow the trend.
We should continue to head down, but we
can't do that without a retracement. So
I anticipated for this market to create
this retracement somewhere up into here
and then it can potentially continue
going to the downside. So I yes indeed
did take a high-risisk trade because I
was trading this retracement. I was
trading the pullback for the lower high
to then create the new lower low. This
is considered a high-risisk trade
because I'm trading against the trend.
I'm not trading with the trend. Trading
with the trend would be looking for
opportunities to sell. would be waiting
for that retracement to then enter the
market to the downside. Buying is
basically like if I was catching a
falling knife, but if you see that the
knife is right at the floor, I think
it's good to catch. And that's exactly
what we did in this trade here. And I
don't recommend for you to catch falling
knives. I don't recommend for you to
pick the bottoms of the markets how I
did in this case here. This is something
that I did because it had many, many,
many reasons for this trade to go to the
upside. This is purely based off of a
almost once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
because we're approaching the lowest
point that we have ever been at. If the
market was in the middle of a move like
this and it was at a low point, I would
not be taking this trade. But since we
have been at the lowest point the market
has literally ever been, as you can see
here, it just simply makes sense. But in
theory, you should never ever take these
type of trades. They're very high risk.
I took it breaking my trading plan
slightly, but aside from that,
everything else made sense. This is the
type of trade that you only take on an
account that you don't want to risk the
money you have made on taking proper
trades or you take this on a high-risisk
account where you don't really care on
the outcome and you're more testing
these high-risk trades and how you
personally are going to react to that
outcome of it, which is very important.
And this is just my first week getting
out of my losing streak. Simply one week
has already engulfed 50% of the losses
that I lost in over a month. Now, this
is because I have proper risk
management. This is because I'm very
patient and I'm taking the right trades.
I actually have a video for you guys
that teaches you my strategy more in
depth, which I'm going to leave it for
you guys right here. It's literally
free. Teaches my strategy completely
from top to bottom to get a better
understanding how you can properly
analyze the markets exactly how I do.
And I'm not going to let any losing
streak or any winning streak get the
best of me because you're simply
supposed to take trades when they make
sense. Doesn't matter if you win five
times in a row or lose five times in a
row. Just simply probability and having
a good strategy. And that's what that
video is about. Hope you guys enjoyed
this video. Make sure you guys hit that
like and subscribe button and I'll see
you guys in the next